(
"ai_sub_version": "2.6.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 13,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
【 3D LIVE 】新3Dお披露目！
[3D LIVE] New 3D Debut!
重大告知あり！
Major Announcement!
ゲーミングソングライブ開催だああ！
Gaming Song Live is happening!
こんこよりー！
Konkoyori!
せーの！
Ready, set!
こんこよべーす！
Konkoyo Base!
ハイ！
Hai!
#こより実験中ですよ！
#KoyoriInTheLab!
OK! フー！
OK! Fuu!
どーも、どーも！
Thanks, thanks!
どーですか、ハイ！
How's this? Yes!
やったー！
Yay!
こよりスケッチでーす！
It's Koyori Sketch!
デレーン！
De-re-n!
ハイ！
Hai!
せーの！
Ready, set!
勉強しろし 全感
Study up, total sensation!
リマインド 全感
Remind, total sensation!
こよりの朝食はネーム
Koyori's breakfast is drafts!
こよー！ヘルプ！
Koyo-! Help!
うわー！本気だー！
Uwa-! I'm serious!
嘘なんでー！見当
It's a lie! Just guessing
かわいいですかー？
Am I cute?
OK! こんこよべーす！
OK! Konkoyo Base!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! I made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a drink!
ちなみにすだちは好きです
By the way, I like sudachi!
ハイ！お肉！全感
Hai! Meat! Total sensation!
冷凍うどんは常備してます
I always have frozen udon stocked!
どーですか、ハイ、やったー！
How's this? Yes, yay!
証明完了 Q.E.D.
Proof complete, Q.E.D.
コップだろコップ！
It's a cup, right? A cup!
こよりにはトッピングのスキル
Koyori has the topping skill!
ご賞味あれ？ ういーういーういー
Care for a taste? Wee wee wee!
うわー！起きませんねー！
Uwa-! You won't wake up!
思い知りますよー！
I'll make you realize!
こよよのプログラムは完璧！
Koyoyo's program is perfect!
ハイ！いけこよー！
Hai! Go Koyo!
うー！やったー！
U-! Yay!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! I made it in time!
私の戦闘力 53万です
My power level is 530,000!
こよの助手は優秀です
Koyo's assistant is excellent!
目指せ！トップオブ小鳥だよ
Aim for it! I'm the top bird!
だけども雨で チョコが好き
But in the rain, I like chocolate!
あー 150 50
Ah, 150 50!
ジュースは飲み物ではありません
Juice is not a drink!
トンカツラーメン ダー！
Tonkatsu Ramen! Da-!
しっぽも振って ダメです
Wagging tail too? No good!
みんなの応援が必要です
Everyone's support is needed!
せーの！こんこよべー！
Ready, set! Konkoyobe-!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! I made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a drink!
ちなみにすだちは好きです
By the way, I like sudachi!
ハイ！お肉！全感
Hai! Meat! Total sensation!
冷凍うどんは常備してます
I always have frozen udon stocked!
どーですか、ハイ、やったー！
How's this? Yes, yay!
せーの！こっこよー！
Ready, set! Kokkoyo-!
こより は マヨネーズ で 回復 した
Koyori recovered with mayonnaise.
助手くんが仲間になった！
Joshu-kun joined the party!
AIこよりが仲間になった！
AI Koyori joined the party!
もふこよが仲間になった！
Mofukoyo joined the party!
ヘイ！
Hey!
カロスを照らすあの朝日のように
Like the morning sun that shines on Kalos,
熱いニトロチャージでいくぜ！
Let's go with a hot Nitro Charge!
さあ 進もうぜ いつでも準備は OK
Come on, let's move forward, always ready.
かたやぶり 変幻自在で
Breaking the mold, with ever-changing form,
重なり合う想いがシンクロして
our overlapping feelings synchronize,
決して消えない絆になるから
becoming a bond that will never fade.
どこまでも強くなれる
We can become stronger than ever,
俺たちなら
if it's us!
いくぜ！
Let's go!
激しく燃えるバトル
A fiercely burning battle!
いくぜ！
Let's go!
ピンチはチャンスだぜ
A pinch is a chance!
いくぜ！
Let's go!
起死回生
A comeback from the brink,
絶対にあきらめない
I will never give up!
俺たちはあきらめない
We will never give up!
ヘイ！
Hey!
たとえどんな壁が道をふさいだって
No matter what wall blocks our path,
いつでも当たって砕けろで
we'll always dive right in and smash through.
さあ この手で勝利の星を掴むんだ
Come on, with these hands, grasp the star of victory!
折れない不屈の心で
With an unbreakable, indomitable heart,
俺たちはいつでもどんな時も
we are always, no matter when,
同じ心で繋がってるから
connected by the same heart.
何度でも立ち上がるぜ
We'll stand up again and again,
お前となら
if I'm with you!
博衣こより生誕Live 2026 見に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my Birthday Live 2026!
神ゲーたちの神ゲームソングをいっぱい詰め込んでるの。最後まで楽しんでいってね！
I've packed in tons of god-tier game songs. Enjoy!
いくぜ！
Let's go!
勝ちも負ける痛みも
Winning, or the pain of losing...
いくぜ！
Let's go!
何でも分け合える
...we can share it all.
いくぜ！
Let's go!
仲間がいる
Because I have my friends,
俺たちは一人じゃない
we are not alone!
いくぜ！
Let's go!
激しく燃えるバトル
A fiercely burning battle!
いくぜ！
Let's go!
ピンチはチャンスだぜ
A pinch is a chance!
いくぜ！
Let's go!
起死回生
A comeback from the brink,
絶対にあきらめない
I will never give up!
いくぜ！
Let's go!
譲れない夢がある
I have a dream I won't give up on.
いくぜ！
Let's go!
必ずゲットだぜ
I'll definitely catch it!
いくぜ！
Let's go!
手を伸ばして
Reach out your hand,
いつか描いた未来へ
to the future we once envisioned,
誰も知らない世界へ
to a world that no one knows!
さあ
Come on,
上げてくぜ 100万ボルト
turn it up—a million volts!
そう
Yes,
立ち向かって共にいこうぜ
let's stand up and go together,
見たことのない夢の向こうまで
to the other side of a dream never seen before!
はーい！みんなー！こんこよー！
Hi everyone! Kon-koyo!
ホロライブ6期生、秘密結社holoXの頭脳、博衣こよりだよー！
It's Hakui Koyori, the brains of holoX, Hololive 6th gen!
改めて、今日は博衣こより生誕Live 2026にお越しいただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to my Birthday Live 2026 today!
コメントもいっぱいありがとう！イエーイ！かっこよ！見えてるよ！ありがとう！
Thanks for all the comments! Yay! 'Cool'! I see you! Thank you!
ということで、ライブの感想やスクショは
So, for live impressions and screenshots,
ハッシュタグ「#博衣こより生誕Live2026」を
use the hashtag #HakuiKoyoriBirthdayLive2026
つけてたくさん...
and post lots of them...
ポストしてください！
Please post about it!
目指せトレンド入り、よろしくう！
Let's aim for the trends! Thank you!
はい、ということで、ちょっと息が整ってないですけど...
Okay, so, I'm a bit out of breath...
さて、今年の生誕ライブ、テーマは『ゲームソングライブ』です！
Now, the theme for this year's birthday live is 'Game Song Live'!
これまでたくさんやってきた実況配信で一緒に遊んできた思い出のゲームや...
From games we've played together in past live streams...
こよりが、大好きーなゲーム関連の楽曲をたくさん詰め込みました。
To songs from games I love, I've packed so much into this.
最後まで全力で楽しんでいってね！
Enjoy yourself to the fullest until the end!
ということで、1曲目は大好きなポケモンのXYZを歌わせていただきました。ね、助手くん。
So, for the first song, I sang XYZ from Pokemon. Right, Assistant-kun?
「俺はこいつと旅に出る」っていうことです。はい。
It's like, 'I'm going on a journey with this guy.' Yes.
Xでセトリ予想もね、みんなにたくさんしてもらってたんですけど、
I saw many of your setlist predictions on X,
ポケモンの予想は結構多かったけど、XYZ当てられてる人は結構少なかったです。
and while many guessed Pokemon, few guessed XYZ.
当たった君、おめでとう！
Congratulations to those who got it right!
ま、この曲は、Z-Aが発売になったっていうのもあるんですけど、
Well, this song was chosen partly because Z-A was announced,
歌詞がめっちゃ良くて、実はこよりにもぴったりな曲なので選びました。
but also because the lyrics are perfect for me.
さあ、この後も自分の予想が当たってるかなーって、ドキドキしながら楽しんでいってください。
Now, keep guessing and enjoy the rest of the show with excitement.
新3Dお披露目もあるからね！絶対最後まで見てってね！
There's a new 3D reveal coming too! Watch until the end!
それでは、そろそろ次の曲。
Now, it's time for the next song.
ゲームの世界へ、どうぞ！
Welcome to the game world!
エアーマンが倒せない
Can't Defeat Airman
気がついたら同じ面ばかりプレイして
Before I knew it, I was playing the same stage over and over
そしていつも同じ場所で死ぬ
And I always end up dying in the same spot
あきらめずに消える足場に挑戦するけど
I don't give up and keep trying those disappearing platforms
すぐに下に落ちるよ
But I fall down immediately
アイテム2号があれば楽に
If I just had Item 2, I could easily
向こうの岸まで着くけれど
reach the other side, but...
何回やっても 何回やっても
No matter how many times I try, no matter how many times I try
エアーマンが倒せないよ
I can't defeat Airman
あの竜巻 何回やってもよけれない
That tornado, no matter how many times I try, I can't dodge it
後ろに回って 撃ち続けても
Even if I get behind him and keep shooting
いずれは風に飛ばされる
Eventually, I'll be blown away by the wind
タイム連打も 試してみたけど
I tried spamming the time button too
竜巻相手じゃ意味がない
But it's useless against a tornado
だから次は絶対勝つために
So, to make sure I win next time
僕はE缶だけは最後までとっておく
I'll save my E-tanks until the very end
気がついたらライフも少ししかない
Before I knew it, my life was almost gone
そしていつもそこでE缶使う
And I always end up using an E-tank right there
あきらめずにエアーマンまでたどりつくけれど
I don't give up and manage to reach Airman, but...
すぐに残機なくなる
I soon run out of lives
リーフシールドがあれば楽に
If I just had the Leaf Shield, I could easily
エアーマンを倒せるけど
defeat Airman, but...
何回やっても 何回やっても
No matter how many times I try, no matter how many times I try
ウッドマンが倒せないよ
I can't defeat Woodman
落ちるコノハは何回やってもよけれない
Those falling leaves, no matter how many times I try, I can't dodge them
後ろに下がって 距離をとっても
Even if I back away to keep my distance
いずれは距離を詰められる
Eventually, he closes in on me
タイム連打も 試してみたけど
I tried spamming the time button too
あいつのジャンプはくぐれない
But I can't slide under his jump
だから次は絶対勝つために
So, to make sure I win next time
僕はE缶だけは最後までとっておく
I'll save my E-tanks until the very end
アイテム2号があれば楽に
If I just had Item 2, I could easily
向こうの岸まで着くけれど
reach the other side, but...
何回やっても 何回やっても
No matter how many times I try, no matter how many times I try
エアーマンが倒せないよ
I can't defeat Airman
竜巻なんか何回やっても避けられない
No matter how many times I try, I can't dodge those tornadoes.
後ろに回って撃ち続けても いずれは風に飛ばされる
Even if I get behind him and keep shooting, I'll eventually be blown away by the wind.
タイム連打も試してみたけど 竜巻相手じゃ意味がない
I even tried rapid-firing with Time, but it's useless against the tornadoes.
だから次は絶対勝つために 僕はE缶だけは最後まで取っておく
So to make sure I win next time, I'm saving my E-Tanks until the very end.
倒せないよ
I can't beat him.
ロボのテーマ
Robo's Theme
カエルのテーマ
Frog's Theme
Melodies of Life
果てもなく彷徨っていた
I was wandering endlessly,
手がかりもなく探し続けた
Searching without a clue...
あなたがくれた思い出を
The memories you gave me...
心を癒す
...they heal my heart.
歌にして
Into a song.
約束もすることもなく
Without making any promises,
かわす言葉もきめたりもせず
Without even deciding on words to exchange,
抱きしめ、そしてたしかめた
I embraced, and then confirmed.
日々は二度とかえらぬ
Those days will never return.
記憶の中の
Within my memories...
手をふるあなたは
...you wave your hand.
私の
My...
名を呼ぶことが出来る
...you will always be able to call my name.
あふれるその涙を
Taking those overflowing tears,
輝く勇기에変えて
And changing them into shining courage,
いのちはつづく
Life goes on.
夜を越え
Crossing through the night,
疑うことのない
With no more doubt,
明日へとつづく
It continues into tomorrow.
飛ぶ鳥のむこうの空へ
To the sky beyond the flying birds,
いくつもの記憶 預けただろう
I wonder how many memories I've entrusted.
はかない希望も夢も
Fleeting hopes and dreams as well,
とどかぬ場所にわすれて
Forgotten in a place they can't reach.
めぐりあうのは
The fact that we met...
偶然と言えるの
...can it be called a coincidence?
別れる時がかならず来るのに
Even though the time to part will surely come.
消えゆく運命でも
Even if it's a fading destiny,
君が生きているかぎり
As long as you are living,
いのちはつづく
Life goes on.
永遠に その力の限り
Forever, with all of its strength,
どこまでも
Wherever it may go...
たとえ私が死のうとも
Even if I should die,
君が生きているかぎり
As long as you are living,
いのちはつづく
Life goes on.
永遠に その力の限り
Forever, with all of its strength,
どこまでもつづく
It will continue on forever.
君の瞳に映る
When reflected in your eyes
私は何色ですか
What color am I?
赤深き望むなら
If you wish for deep red
渡そう陽の光を
I shall give you the light of the sun
「キミガタメ」
“Kimi ga tame”
悲しみが溢れ
Overflowing with sadness
瞼閉じました
I closed my eyes
こぼれた雫は
The spilled droplets
心に染みゆく
Sink deep into my heart
行き渡る波は
The waves that reach everywhere
弱くまじえます
Weakly intermingle
とどけし揺りかご
The cradle that was delivered
眠りをさそう
Invites sleep
夢に懐かしい
In dreams, a nostalgic...
面影を探す
...vestige I seek
手を伸ばし
Reaching out my hand
強く抱きしめたくなる
I want to hold you tight
君の瞳に映る
When reflected in your eyes
私は何色ですか
What color am I?
赤深き望むなら
If you wish for deep red
渡そう高き空を
I shall give you the high sky
不安定な神様
Unstable God
繰り返す出会いと別れ
Repeating meetings and partings
また会えるその日まで
Until the day we can meet again
時かける旅人
Time-traveling travelers
あなたが泣いている
You are crying
流るる涙の雨
In the rain of flowing tears
泣くなとは言わない
I won't tell you not to cry
心悲しくて
Because my heart is sad too
生きとし生けるもの
All living things
何かを背負いながら
While carrying something
見えない鎖に
By invisible chains
つながれている
They are tied
どれほど救われただろう
How much was I saved...
あどけない笑顔を
...by that innocent smile
なくしたくはない
I don't want to lose it
不安定な神様
Unstable God
繰り返すこと見ない
Unable to see the repeats
生まれて そして
Being born, and then
死んでゆく運命
The fate of dying
引き継いだ夢と愛を
The dreams and love I inherited
育て守り 拓く運命
Nurturing, protecting, and opening up destiny
掛け違えた世界で
In a mismatched world
探す旅 引き裂かれても
On a journey of searching, even if torn apart
また会える と信じて
Believing that we can meet again
時駆ける旅人
A traveler through time
不安定な神様
Unstable God
繰り返す過去と未来
Repeating pasts and futures
生まれ そして死んでゆく運命
Born, and then a destiny to die
掛け違えた世界で
In a mismatched world
繰り返す出会いと別れ
Repeating meetings and partings
また会えるその日まで
Until the day we can meet again
時駆ける旅人
A traveler through time
また会えるその日まで
Until the day we can meet again
時駆ける旅人
A traveler through time
はい！ということで、Suaraさんにお越しいただき
Yes! And so, Suara-san came here...
一緒に歌わせていただきました！
and sang together with me!
Suaraさん、自己紹介をいただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
Suara-san, would you mind introducing yourself?
はい、えーSuaraです。
Hi, I'm Suara.
『うたわれるもの』シリーズの主題歌を
I sing many of the theme songs
たくさん歌っている者です。
for the "Utawarerumono" series.
はいー！ようこそー！
Yes! Welcome!
こよりさん！
Koyori-san!
そうなんです。え、実はですね、『うたわれるもの』というゲーム...
That's right. Actually, the game "Utawarerumono"...
昨年約3ヶ月間かけてシリーズの三部作を
last year I spent about 3 months
実況プレイさせていただいたんですけれども...
doing a Let's Play of the trilogy...
その『うたわれるもの』、本当に曲がめちゃくちゃいいのですが...
Those "Utawarerumono" songs are really good...
その歌をほぼ全てSuaraさんが歌っていらっしゃるというのです！
And almost all of them are sung by Suara-san!
はい（笑）
Yes (laughs).
もう、耳が今日本当に幸せで！
Gosh, my ears are just so happy today!
いや、こちらこそですよ本当に。
No, same here, really.
もう本当、恐縮、恐れ多い状態なんですけど、
I'm really just... so humbled and overwhelmed,
ありがとうございます！
but thank you so much!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
Suaraさんには実は、4周年の時に
Actually, I received a message from Suara-san
逆凸でメッセージも頂戴しておりまして。
during my 4th anniversary through a call-in.
その時に、いつか一緒に歌いたいというのも、
At that time, I sent a very passionate love call
こよりも結構熱烈なラブコールをさせていただいていたんです。
saying I wanted to sing together someday.
その思いを本日叶えることができました！
And that wish came true today!
えー、あ、ちょっと質問が何個かあるんですけど...
Uh, oh, I have a few questions...
はい。
Yes.
実はあの、『うたわれるもの』の実況してた時に、
Actually, when I was doing the Let's Play of 'Utawarerumono',
最終回で...
in the final episode...
Suaraさんがコメントしてくださりまして！
Suara-san left a comment!
こよりの実況ちょっとご覧くださったと思うんですけど...
I believe you watched some of my Let's Play...
はい、はい。
Yes, yes.
あの、見られますか？実況とかって普段。
Do you... do you usually watch Let's Plays?
いや、ちょっと実はですね、ちょっと初めて見させていただいて...
Well, actually, that was the first time I ever watched one...
ええっ！？そうなんですか！？
What!? Really!?
あの、アクアプラスのスタッフの方とかも...
The staff at Aquaplus...
「こよりさんっていう『うたわれる』配信してるよ」って言って...
told me, "There's someone named Koyori-san streaming 'Utawareru'!"
情報は聞いていたんですよね。
So I had heard about it.
えー！
Oh!
私のライブに来てくれるファンの、方たちからも...
And also from the fans who come to my live concerts...
聞いていたんですよ。「ぜひ見てみてください」って言って。
I had heard them say, "Please give it a watch."
それで見させていただいたっていうのが最終回だったんですけど...
And so, the one I watched was that final episode...
そうだったんですね！恐縮ですが！
So that's how it was! I'm so flattered!
こよりさんの『うたわれるもの』への愛が、すごい溢れてて。
Koyori-san's love for 'Utawarerumono' was just overflowing.
本当に見てて、最後までずっと見させていただいて...
Truly, watching it, I watched it all the way to the end...
うわああ！
Uwaaa!
「コメント送りたいな、でも早くしないと終わっちゃう！」って思いながら...
"I want to send a comment, but if I don't hurry, it'll end!"
同じ部屋に、私の息子がいたんですけど。
My son was in the same room as me.
え！息子さんまで！？
What! Your son too!?
息子に「コメントちょっと送ってみていいと思う？」って聞いて...
I asked my son if it was okay to send a comment,
聞いたら、「いいんちゃう」って言って（笑）
and he was like, "Why not?" (laughs).
いい息子さんだー！
What a great son!
本当に震える手でコメント打って...
With my hands literally shaking, I typed the comment...
「早く、エンターキーを...」って。
"Hurry, the Enter key..."
そんな緊張してくださってたんですか！？
You were that nervous!?
「押そか押そか、どうしよう、でもはよ押さな！」みたいな（笑）
"Should I press it, what do I do, I have to press it now!"
はい、それで、もうドキドキしながら、あの、送らせていただいたら、
Yes, and so, with my heart pounding, I sent a comment, and...
スアラさんね、あの、コメント気づいてくださって、
Suara-san, you noticed the comment!
ねー。もう、とっても嬉しかったです！
I did. I was so happy!
こよりもですし、見てた助手くんたちもものすごく、もう、嬉しくて、
I was, and the Assistants watching were also incredibly happy...
やっぱり見ていただけるっていうのが、スアラさんとかアクアプラスさんもそうですし、
To have Suara-san and Aquaplus watching us...
公式の皆様にご覧いただけるって、本当に嬉しく恐縮なことなので、
To have the official staff watching is truly a joy and an honor,
幸せでございました。ありがとうございます。
It was such a blessing. Thank you so much.
もう、すごい楽しくて、見入っちゃいました。本当に。
It was so fun, I was completely mesmerized. Truly.
いやー、嬉しいです！
Oh, I'm so glad!
すごい長時間されてるのが、すごいなと思って、本当に。
I was so impressed that you were doing such a long stream.
はい。もう、そのあとのね、その日の夜も歌枠も聴かせていただいたり、
Yes. And I also listened to your karaoke stream later that night...
おおー、すごい体力だなって思いながら、
I was thinking, "Wow, what incredible stamina!"
それで、楽しんでる「うたわれるもの」が、本当に素晴らしい作品だったから、
And the way you enjoyed "Utawarerumono," which is such a wonderful series...
ですので、その「うたわれるもの」とずっと付き合っていらっしゃるスアラさんですけれども、
So, Suara-san, you've been involved with "Utawarerumono" for a long time...
推しキャラとかっていらっしゃるんですか？
Do you have a favorite character?
推しキャラですか。推しキャラはやっぱり、ちょっとエルルゥってことに…
A favorite character? Well, I suppose my favorite would have to be Eluluu...
えっ、ってことは！ エルルゥってことに…しておかないとね、
Oh, which means...! I have to say Eluluu...
ちょっとフォークで刺されるかもしれない…
Or else I might get poked with a fork...
あ、あれ？ もしかして、あの、仲が良い…
Oh? Could it be that you're close with...
あのね、中の人の、柚木涼香さんとね、
You know, the voice actress, Ryoka Yuzuki-san...
とっても仲良くさせていただいてて、
We are very good friends,
本当にアニメの放送のときからですね、
Since the anime was first broadcast,
2006年からずっと仲良くさせていただいてるっていう。
We've been close ever since 2006.
20年！
20 years!
そうですね、20年。 すごい！
Yes, 20 years. Amazing!
はい。それはエルルゥ推し…ですね！
So, it's Eluluu for me!
ということもあって、エルルゥ推しということでお願いします。
For that reason as well, please put me down as an Eluluu fan.
こよりはもう、アルルゥが大好きなので、
Koyori loves Aruruu,
エルルゥ、アルルゥで、姉妹で！
So with Eluluu and Aruruu, it's the sisters!
姉妹で！ 嬉しいです！
The sisters! I'm so happy!
ということで、もっともっとお話ししたいんですけれども、時間が来てしまいまして、
I'd love to chat more, but our time is unfortunately up...
本当に今日は一緒に歌っていただき、ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for singing with me today!
ありがとうございました。こよりさんの本当に柔らかい、優しい、暖かい声に包まれながら、
Thank you. Being enveloped by Koyori-san's truly soft, kind, and warm voice,
私も一緒に歌えて、本当に幸せでした。
I was so happy to be able to sing with you.
恐縮でございました！ ありがとうございます！
I'm honored! Thank you so much!
またぜひ、いろいろご一緒させていただける機会があれば嬉しいです！
I'd love to have another chance to work with you again!
ぜひぜひ、よろしくお願いします！
Absolutely, I look forward to it!
ありがとうございます！ ということで、スアラさんでした！ ありがとうございました！
Thank you! That was Suara-san! Thank you very much!
やがて女はきれいになるだろう
Eventually, a woman will become beautiful...
あーうんけとんま！
A-un-ke-ton-ma!
だいスキ！
Love it!
だいスキ！ だいスキ！
Love it! Love it!
ドットに媚びてんの人生
My life is sucking up to pixels
本当の自分出せない
I can't show my true self
あまのじゃくがセクシー
Contrarian is sexy
いい女並んで
Good women standing side-by-side
信じて返し
Believe and reciprocate
お褒め素敵だよ
Compliments are wonderful
輝きたい！ 愛されたい！
I want to shine! I want to be loved!
歴史や方程式置かないで
Don't put down history or equations
かなりや感じ性生きたい
I want to live with quite a bit of sensitivity
ああ悲しい歌流れる
Ah, a sad song is playing
町のあなた歩く
You walking through the town
涙顔流れちゃう 涙顔流れちゃう
My tear-stained face is showing...
涙顔流れちゃうのは…
The reason my tear-stained face is showing...
どうしてなんだろう
I wonder why
ワン・ツー・スリーで
On the count of one, two, three
ぺかっぱ破れて
The paper is torn
誰も信じられなちゃ
I can't believe anyone
泣きたいだけなればいい
It's okay to just want to cry
ワン・ツー・スリーで
On the count of one, two, three
だからもっと恋して
So fall in love even more
トキメキ中過ぎて
Too much heart-pounding
周りが見えなくなって
Losing sight of my surroundings
できて万歳！
Success! Banzai!
だいスキ！ だいスキ！
Love it! Love it!
こっち見て！
Look this way!
マジだいスキ！
I really love it!
だいスキ！ だいスキ！
Love it! Love it!
できて万歳！
Success! Banzai!
愛♡スクリーム！
Ai♡Scream!
教えて もっと あなたのこと
Tell me more about you
Tell me more more more, Tell me more more more
聞かせて もっと あなたの声
Let me hear more of your voice
Let me hear more more more, Let me hear more more more
こんなドキドキ もう抑えられない
I can't suppress this heart-pounding anymore
Oh! I need you, Oh! I need you
友達は卒業 運命の私
Graduating from being friends, my destiny...
見つけてほしいの
...I want you to find it
One! 勇気を出して
One! Gather your courage
Two! 見つめる作戦
Two! Staring strategy
Three! 目と目が合えば
Three! If our eyes meet...
Four! Wow!
止められない Yeah yeah yeah
Can't be stopped, yeah yeah yeah
この恋 この愛で
With this crush, with this love
Melt Melty 溶けちゃうよ
Melt melty, I'm melting
ねえねえねえ 気づいてまいたり
Hey hey hey, notice me
届け 大好き
Reach you, I love you
Ice Cream, Scream 叫びましょう
Ice cream, scream, let's shout
Scream, Ice Cream, OK?
Ice Cream, Scream 叫びましょう
Ice cream, scream, let's shout
Scream, Ice Cream!
こよりちゃん！
Koyori-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
マヨネーズ！
Mayonnaise!
よりも あなた！
More than that, I like you!
AZKiちゃん！
AZKi-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
こしあん つぶあん
Smooth paste, chunky paste
よりも あなた！
More than that, I like you!
ラミィちゃん！
Lamy-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
お酒よりも あなた！
More than alcohol, I like you!
みんな！
Everyone!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
もちろん大好き こよ組！
Of course we love you, Koyo-gumi!
止められない Yeah yeah yeah
Can't be stopped, yeah yeah yeah
この恋 この愛で
With this crush, with this love
Melt Melty 溶けちゃうよ
Melt melty, I'm melting
ねえねえねえ 気づいてまいたり
Hey hey hey, notice me
届け 大好き
Reach you, I love you
Ice Cream, Scream 叫びましょう
Ice cream, scream, let's shout
Scream, Ice Cream, OK?
Ice Cream, Scream 叫びましょう
Ice cream, scream, let's shout
Scream, Ice Cream!
お願い 見つけてまいたり
Please find me
見つけてまいたり
Find me
お願い 気づいてまいたり
Please notice me
気づいてまいたり
Notice me
One! 勇気を出して
One! Gather your courage
Two! 近づく作戦
Two! Approach strategy
Three! 手と手が触れて
Three! If our hands touch...
Four! Wow!
止められない Yeah yeah yeah
Can't be stopped, yeah yeah yeah
この恋 この愛で
With this crush, with this love
Melt Melty 溶けちゃうよ
Melt melty, I'm melting
ねえねえねえ 気づいてまいたり
Hey hey hey, notice me
それは あなた
It's you
Ice Cream, Scream 叫びましょう
Ice cream, scream, let's shout
Scream, Ice Cream, OK?
Ice Cream, Scream 叫びましょう
Ice cream, scream, let's shout
Scream, Ice Cream!
ガツーン!!!
Wham!!!
カッキーン!!
Crack!!
ホームラン
Home Run
カッキーン!!
Crack!!
RELAY
目覚めては繰り返す
Waking up to a repeating...
眠い朝は
...sleepy morning,
襟のネクタイを
I pull my necktie...
きつく締め上げて
...tight.
教室のドアを
When I pass through...
くぐると
...the classroom door,
ほんの少し
I can slightly...
胸を張って
...lift my chest...
歩き出せる
...and start walking.
そんな日常に
Through such an ordinary day,
吹き抜ける風
a wind blows.
聞こえた気がした
I felt like I heard it.
感じた気がしたんだ
I felt like I felt it.
震え出す今この胸で
It starts to tremble, now, in this chest.
もう来る気がした
I felt like it was coming already.
幾億の星が消えて
Millions of stars disappear...
去ってゆくのを
...and fade away;
見送った
I watched them go.
手を振った
I waved my hand.
よかったねと
Saying, 'I'm so glad.'
物語
The story,
永遠の
of eternity.
その終わり
Its end...
目を閉じた
I closed my eyes.
手を振った
I waved my hand.
ありがとう
Thank you.
ぽつり灯り 管制塔
A faint light, control tower
砂嵐の向こうへ
Towards the other side of the sandstorm
祈るよう 綴った
Praying, I wrote down
これからのこと
Things about the future
管制塔より
From the Control Tower
ラジオネーム 匿名希望
Radio name: Anonymous
お便り届いてますか？
Is my letter reaching you?
この世界がいつからか
Ever since this world, at some point,
まるで他人事のように
felt like someone else's business,
やけに静かなので
because it's so awfully quiet,
不安になったのです
I've become anxious.
思い出したのです
I've remembered.
人知れず口を噤んだまま
Without anyone knowing, with my mouth shut tight,
終われないのです
I can't let it end.
それは嫌なのです
I don't want that.
夢ってもっと
Dreams should have been
わがままだったでしょう
more selfish, right?
応えてよ 笑ってよ 気づいてよ
Respond to me, laugh, notice me,
此処に居るのにな
even though I'm right here.
意地悪だなあ
How mean.
誰にも届かない光を
A light that reaches no one,
どうしたら伝えられるのでしょう
how can I ever convey it?
伝えたいのでしょう
I want to convey it, don't I?
どうしても伝えたいよ
I really want to convey it.
ラジオネーム、匿名希望
Radio name, Anonymous
意気地なしなのでしょうか
Is it because I'm a coward?
それともこの世界には
Or is it that in this world...
僕は お邪魔でしょうか
I'm a nuisance?
だとしても綴るよ
Even so, I'll write it down
みっともなく叫ぶよ
I'll scream ungracefully
振られたって好きだよ
Even if I'm rejected, I love you
いいでしょう
It's okay, right?
いいでしょ
Right?
楽しかったよね
It was fun, wasn't it?
悔しかったよね
It was frustrating, wasn't it?
もう独り言は嫌だ
I don't want to talk to myself anymore
「待たせちゃったかな」
"Did I keep you waiting?"
『別に待ってないよ』
"I wasn't waiting at all"
夢と呼んだ
What I called a dream
それも僕だっただけ
Was just me too
もういいかい
Are you ready yet?
応えてよ
Answer me
笑ってよ
Smile for me
気付いてよ
Notice me
此処に居るのにな
Even though I'm right here
意地悪だなぁ
You're so mean
誰にも届かない光を
A light that reaches no one...
僕だけは光と呼び続ける
I alone will continue to call it light
真夜中 管制塔から
In the middle of the night, from the control tower
世界を明かしてやる
I'll illuminate the world
特報
Special News
応えてよ 笑ってよ 気付いてよ
Answer me, smile for me, notice me
此処に居るのにな
Even though I'm right here
意地悪だなぁ
You're so mean
誰にも届かない光を
A light that reaches no one...
どうしたら耐えられるのでしょう
How can I possibly bear this?
どうしても伝えたいよ
I just want to tell you no matter what
管制塔より
From the Control Tower
ライブ終了直後 プレミア公開
Premiere immediately after the live
ということで！
And so!
新曲のお披露目、フルアニメーションMV公開の告知、
The debut of the new song, the announcement of the full animation MV release,
新3Dのお披露目、3個、ドンドンとまとめてやらせていただきましたー！
and the debut of the new 3D—I've presented all three in quick succession!
情報量多かったけど、ついてきてるかな？
There was a lot of information, but are you keeping up?
はい、ちょっとね、新3Dが可愛すぎて気になっちゃうと思うんですけど、
Yes, well, I'm sure you're all curious because the new 3D is just too cute,
まずはオリ曲の話からさせてください！
but first, let me talk about the original song!
お披露目させていただいたのは、新曲「管制塔より」！
What I performed was the new song "Kanseitou Yori"!
ついに、あの堀江晶太さんに書き下ろしていただきました！
Finally, I had the one and only Shota Horie write this for me!
みんな、どうだった？エモい？良かった？
How was it, everyone? Was it emotional? Was it good?
はい、そしてですね、今ちょっと映像も流して「すごい」って言ってくれててめっちゃ嬉しいんですけど、
Yes, and right now the video is playing and I'm so happy you're saying it's "amazing",
このライブ終了直後に、フルアニメーションMVがプレミア公開されます！
immediately after this live ends, the full animation MV will have its premiere!
たぶんもうマネちゃんがポチっとしてくれてると思います。
I think my manager is already clicking the button.
世界観がめちゃくちゃこだわられている映像作品になっているので、
It's a visual work with a world-view that has been extremely carefully crafted,
何回も見て、聴いて、そしてちょっと世界観の考察とかしてみてください！
so please watch and listen to it many times, and maybe try speculating about the setting!
そして、お待たせしました、新3D！
And now, the moment you've been waiting for, the new 3D!
あ、ちょっと待って！一個言い忘れました。
Oh, wait! I forgot one thing.
さっきの曲「管制塔より」、24時にリリースもあります！よろしくお願いします！
The song "Kanseitou Yori" will also be released at midnight! Please check it out!
そしてですね、お待たせしました！新3D！
And now, thank you for waiting! The new 3D!
どう？可愛い？可愛い？可愛い？
How is it? Is it cute? Is it cute? Is it cute?
はい、もっとね、余すことなく見せたいんだけど、
Yes, I want to show you even more of it without holding anything back,
ちょっと、ももこママの、あの、あれ、いつもよりすごい近くなったんじゃないかなと思います！
but I think Momoko-mama's taste—well, that thing—is much closer than usual!
このあとのメン限ライブでね、撮影会もしまして、さらに細かく見せちゃうので、
In the members-only live after this, we'll have a photoshoot and I'll show it in even more detail,
ぜひメン限ライブも来てください！
so please come to the members-only live too!
メン限ライブでは本編で歌えなかったあのゲームの、みんなが大好きな曲、
In the members-only live, I'll sing that song from that game everyone loves that I couldn't sing in the main stream,
キンキンキンも歌うよ！お楽しみに！
I'll sing "Kin Kin Kin" too! Look forward to it!
じゃあ一つだけ、新3Dのめっちゃ変わったポイント教えちゃうと、
Well, let me tell you just one point that's really changed about the new 3D,
獣耳が揺れます！
The animal ears twitch!
うわー！可愛いー！
Whoa! So cute!
に！ はい、ということでね！
Ni! Yes, so anyway!
え、あ、あとトレンド1位も
Oh, and thank you so much
本当にありがとうございました。
for #1 on the trends.
今日無理かなーって思ってたんで、
I thought it might be impossible today,
めっちゃ嬉しかったし、トレンド爆散、
so I was really happy. The trends exploded,
なんかすごいいっぱい入ってたみたいで、
it seems like a lot of them got in,
本当にありがとう！
thank you so much!
それでは、もうひとつ大事なお知らせです。ドン！
Now, here's another important announcement. Bam!
博衣こより誕生日記念グッズ2026が
Hakui Koyori Birthday Celebration Goods 2026
発売されます！イエーイ！
are going on sale! Yay!
さっそく詳細を見ていきましょう。
Let's check the details right away.
まず1つ目はこちら！
First up is this!
もふこよりにもなれる！？2Wayブランケット。
You can even become Mofukoyori!? 2Way Blanket.
お部屋でゲームを楽しんでいるこよりの
It features an illustration of Koyori
描き下ろしイラストです。
enjoying games in her room.
イラストはもちろん、ももこママ！
The illustration is, of course, by Momoko-mama!
これ丸めるともふこよりに早変わりして、
If you roll this up, it quickly becomes Mofukoyori,
持ち運びも楽ちんだし、
making it easy to carry around,
そのまま飾っても可愛いですね。
and it's cute to just display as is.
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
ボイスキーホルダー 〜ゲーム実況編〜
Voice Keychain - Game Commentary Edition -
待望のボイスキーホルダーが出ました！
The long-awaited voice keychain is here!
こよりの録り下ろしボイスが入っているもので、
It contains newly recorded voices of Koyori,
今回はライブに合わせて、
and this time, to match the live,
ゲーム実況中っぽいセリフ、絶叫が
it includes 6 types of lines and screams
6種類入っております。
that sound like they're from a game stream.
セリフはこよが考えました！
I came up with the lines!
イラストはなもり先生です。
The illustration is by Namori-sensei.
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
こより監督ぬいぐるみスマホスタンド。
Director Koyori Plushie Smartphone Stand.
あのこより監督がついにぬいぐるみになったよ！
That Director Koyori has finally become a plushie!
可愛い！
So cute!
そのまま飾るもよし、
You can display it as is,
スマホスタンドにもなるので超便利です。
or use it as a smartphone stand, so it's handy.
絶対ゲットしてね！
Be sure to get one!
最後はこちら！
Last one is this!
ゲーム機風カードホルダー！
Game Console Style Card Holder!
特典のチェキ風ブロマイドとか
It's a card holder where you can carry around
ホロカも入れられて、持ち運べちゃうホルダーです。
bonus cheki-style bromide or Holocards.
中に入っている台紙のイラストは
I, Koyo-chan, drew the illustration
こよちゃんが描きました。
on the backing paper inside.
ゲーム機風のデザインもレトロゲームっぽくて可愛くない？
Isn't the retro game console design cute?
はい、そしてフルセット特典はこちらです！
Yes, and here are the full set purchase bonuses!
ももこママ描き下ろしのチェキ風ブロマイドがつきます。
It comes with a cheki-style bromide by Momoko-mama.
数量限定版は直筆サインと箔押し、
The limited quantity version includes a handwritten
複製メッセージ入り、
signature, foil stamping, and message,
通常版は箔押しの複製サインとメッセージ入りです。
and the regular version has a duplicated signature.
販売開始が、このあと21時10分にしてあるので、
Sales will start later at 21:10,
皆さん、あの慌てないで大丈夫です。
so everyone, please don't panic.
10分からなので。はい、あの見てってください。
It starts at 10 past. Yes, please check it out.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you very much.
さらに特典ASMRボイスもつきます。
There's also a bonus ASMR voice.
毎年恒例の、君の誕生日を
The annual tradition, the 2026 version of the
逆に祝っちゃうASMRボイス2026版。
ASMR voice where I celebrate your birthday.
こちらですね、毎年みんな誕生日まで
I'm really happy that everyone waits
我慢して聴いて、ワーイってなっているの
until their birthday to listen and get excited.
すごく嬉しく思っています。
It makes me very happy.
ぜひゲットしてください。
Please be sure to get it.
はい、ということでね！怒涛のお知らせでしたが、
Yes, so, those were a lot of announcements,
可愛いでしょ？
but aren't they cute?
みんなが可愛いって言ってくれてて、こよ嬉しいよ！
I'm so happy that everyone says they're cute!
表情とかもちょっと変わったんですよ。
My expressions have changed a bit too.
にゃー！
Nyaa!
これがドヤ顔になりました。
This became my smug face.
あとは、キリッ！ エヘッ！
Also, sharp! Ehe!
こんな表情もできるようになりました。
I can make expressions like this now.
面研をお楽しみに！
Look forward to the face reveal!
ということで今日は、博衣こより生誕ライブ2026、
So, thank you all for coming to see the
ゲームソングライブに見に来てくれて、ありがとう！
Hakui Koyori Birthday Live 2026, Game Song Live!
このあとですね、新曲のアニメMV公開と、
After this, the new song's MV will be released,
メン限ライブ。あ、ですね、
followed by a members-only live. Oh, that's right,
アニメMV公開見て、で10分からグッズ買って、
watch the anime MV, buy goods from 10 past,
15分からメン限ライブって感じで、
and then the members-only live from 15 past,
ゆっくり順番に行けるようになっているので、
so you can go through them at a relaxed pace,
慌てず、駆けず、何だろ、押さず、でよろしくお願いします。
please don't rush, don't run, and... don't push.
ということで、今日はちょっと遅れちゃったんだけど、
So, it was a bit late today, but I'm so happy
この3Dお披露目して、生誕ライブもできて、
I could show this 3D and have the birthday live,
大好きなゲームソングいっぱいお披露目できて、嬉しかったよ！
and perform so many of my favorite game songs!
みんな本当に見に来てくれて、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to see me!
また会おうね！ ありがとう！
Let's meet again! Thank you!
MV見てねー！ バイバイ！
Watch the MV! Bye-bye!